Guide to the Voices of Brooklyn oral histories 2008.031
Brooklyn Historical Society
- Voices of Brooklyn oral histories: Veterans and wartime, 1998-; 2008.031.7
  - Palo, Michael, 2008 November 18; 2008.031.7.008
    In this interview, Michael Palo talks about being drafted into the Vietnam War after high school, the effects the war had on his personality, his relationships upon his return, his physical wellness, and his children's health. He discusses the way in which veterans are treated by civilians and by the government upon their return to the United States and how that has directly influenced his involvement in various veterans' organizations later in life. He reflects on growing up in Brooklyn as the child of second-generation Italian immigrants and how he lived with his family in a three room apartment with little to no luxuries. In closing, Palo talks about his three marriages and how he feels responsible for the health of his children. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.
    Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Coney Island (New York, N.Y.); Immigrants -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Italian Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Medical care |z United States; Mental health; Nonprofit organizations -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Prospect Heights (New York, N.Y.); Soldiers |x Family relationships |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Soldiers |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Staten Island (New York, N.Y.); Stigma (Social psychology) |z New York (State) |z Kings County; United States |x Politics and government; Vietnam War, 1961-1975 |x Veterans |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Palo, Michael P.; Patriot Guard Riders; United States. Department of Veterans Affairs; Wounded Warrior Project
- Voices of Brooklyn oral histories: Waterfront series, 2017-
  Arrangement
  The oral histories in this series are arranged alphabetically by narrator's last name.
  The six oral history interviews that comprise this series were conducted during 2017 as a part of the research process for Brooklyn Historical Society's Waterfront exhibition.
  - Davenport, Roberta, 2017 October 28; 2008.031.8.001
    Roberta Davenport (1951-) was born to Virginian parents who settled north in Brooklyn. She grew up in the Farragut Houses, as one of the housing project's earliest residents. Davenport attended Marymount Manhattan College, where she studied studio art and elementary education, and received graduate degrees from Teachers College at Columbia University and the Principals Institute of Bank Street. She began a career of teaching and working with elementary-age children at schools in Brooklyn and Stamford, CT, eventually returning to Farragut as Principal of PS 307.
    In this interview, Roberta Davenport (1951-) discusses her childhood and life in Farragut, including her father's work at the Brooklyn Navy Yard, her experiences working with children from a young age, and her education. Davenport describes her experiences at St. Joseph's Children's Services, PS 11, the development of her teaching philosophy, her involvement with the Waterside School in Stamford, CT, and her return to Farragut to become Principal at PS 307. At PS 307, she spearheaded a transformation of the school, strengthening academic programs and support for the children, including introducing involvement with local arts organizations. Interview conducted by Julie Golia.
    This interview can be accessed onsite at Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online at the Oral History Portal.
    Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Stamford (Conn.); Education, Higher -- New York (State) -- New York; Education, Elementary; Elementary school principals; Elementary school teaching; African American teachers; Public schools |z New York (State) |z New York; Davenport, Roberta; Doughtery, Dorothy; Owen, Richard C.; Clay, Mary; Ozawa, Machiko
  - Davis, Crane, 2017 April 7; 2008.031.8.002
    Crane Davis (1945-) was born in Dallas, Texas to two parents in the Marine Corps. Davis received a B.A. in romance languages from Princeton University. He was a reporter at Time Magazine and WNET's Channel Thirteen, living in the woods of Maine in between the two jobs. He worked as an independent speech writer and fought for renters' rights in Brooklyn.
    During the interview, Crane Davis (1945-) describes growing up in New York City and returning as an adult. Davis discusses his involvement in the Vietnam War as a Ma-rine Corps officer, reporting on Gay and Lesbian communities prior to the AIDS ep-idemic, and his experience organizing loft tenants and manufacturers at DUMBO in the 70s and 80s. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.
    Maine; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Albany (N.Y.); Housing policy--New York (State)--New York; Manufacturing industries--United States--History; Landlord and tenant; New York (N.Y.) |x Politics and government; Television broadcasting--Social aspects; Draft; Labor unions--Organizing; Davis, Crane; Time; Princeton University; United States Marine Corps; Collegiate School (New York, N.Y.)
  - Reyna, Diana, 2017 August 17; 2008.031.8.003
    Diana Reyna (1973-) was born to Dominican immigrant parents who settled in Los Sures, Williamsburg, where she was raised. After getting a degree from Pace University, Reyna began a career of politics working in her local Assemblyman's office. From 2001-2013, she was a New York City Council Member for the 34th Council District, and Brooklyn Deputy Borough President from 2014-2017. Currently, Reyna is the founding principal at Diana Reyna Strategic Consulting, LLC.
    In this interview, Diana Reyna (1973-) talks about her childhood in Los Sures, Williamsburg, her community's connection to the waterfront, and her parents' work in the industrial waterfront area. She discusses the changes that took place in her neighborhood and her family's reluctant transition to Bushwick, her initial work in local politics, her approach to government, and the issues she focused on in campaigning for New York City Council. Reyna describes the way the development of the waterfront has changed, the communities that are affected by these changes, and her hopes for the future. Interview conducted by Svetlana Kitto.
    Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Williamsburg (New York, N.Y.); Bushwick (New York, N.Y.); New York (State) |x Politics and government; Municipal government |z New York (State) |z Kings County; City council members; Dominican Americans; Development; Gentrification; Reyna, Diana; Lopez, Vito; Quadrozzi, John
  - Shields, Sienna, 2017 November 8; 2008.031.8.004
    Sienna Shields (1976-) grew up near Anchorage, Alaska. She is African American and studied history at Lewis and Clark College in Portland. She was a member of DUMBA and lived there from 2002 till DUMBA were evicted in 2007. Shields is a former model, a painter, exhibiting artist, and member of the HOWDOYOUSAYYAMINAFRICAN Collective.
    In the interview, Sienna Shields (1976-) describes her journey from Alaska to Brooklyn as well as her experiences living in the DUMBA collective, working as an artist in New York City, and forming relationships as a queer woman in the early 2000s until DUMBA's eviction from Brooklyn. Shields also discusses the effects of gentrification in Dumbo and the filming of Shortbus at DUMBA. Interview conducted by Svetlana Kitto.
    DUMBO Historic District (New York, N.Y.); San Francisco (Calif.); Portland (Or.); Sexual minority community; Lesbian community; Gentrification; Police |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Collective settlements; Anarchists; African American women artists; Art centers; Performance art--Exhibitions; Motion picture film; Shields, Sienna
  - Sun, Carol, 2017 June 4; 2008.031.8.005
    Carol Sun was born in 1958 in the North Bronx (Kingsbridge/Fordham Hill) as the second of three children. She attended The High School of Music and Art, now known as LaGuardia, in Manhattan, for dance and painting. After graduating from high school, Sun went on to study art and design and The Cooper Union. She moved to DUMBO after graduating from Cooper Union in 1979. Sun is an artist who works with painting and glass and other media; one of her public art pieces is on view at the MTA's 167th Street 4-train station. She worked as a graphic designer, focusing on branding, for many years and she taught design as well. Sun has also worked as an educator teaching at Manhattan Early College School for Advertising for seventeen years.
    In this interview, Carol Sun (1958-) talks about her childhood experiences growing up in the Bronx in the '50s and '60s in a neighborhood where there were not many families with a Chinese heritage. She also recalls the gender dynamics in her family and her choice to become a dancer and artist rather than pursue STEM fields. Sun describes walking around the neighborhood that is now known as DUMBO in the 1970s looking for artist-occupied buildings. She describes marrying her husband at Barge Music, in the very early days of its existence, because she was friends with the founder, Olga Bloom. Sun describes three waves of development and change in DUMBO that she has witnessed in her 38 years there. She recalls how Crane and Monte Davis organized tenants in DUMBO and how their building tenants were eventually able to buy their building from city with the help of City Council member Kenneth K. Fisher and a lawyer Jed Marcus. Sun talks about how her art is inspired by place and narrative and she describes several projects inspired by her DUMBO neighborhood. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.
    Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Bronx (New York, N.Y.); Kingsbridge (New York, N.Y.); DUMBO Historic District (New York, N.Y.); Immigrants -- United States; Chinese American artists; Factories; Manufacturing industries; Deindustrialization; Real estate development; Waterfronts; Development; Gentrification; Women artists; Sun, Carol; Gair, Robert; Davis, Crane; Davis, Monte; Rachman, Jerry; Walentas, David; Fisher, Kenneth K.; Marcus, Jed; DeMaio, Mario; Cooper Union for the Advancement of Science and Art; Fiorello H. LaGuardia High School of Music & Art and Performing Arts (New York, N.Y.)
  - Walentas, David and Jane, 2017 August 22; 2008.031.8.006
    David Walentas was born in Rochester, New York in 1938. He received a BA in Engineering from the University of Virginia and MBA from the UVA Darden School of Business. David Walentas is a billionaire developer known for his company, Two Trees, which owns properties in Dumbo, Brooklyn.
    Jane Zimmerman Walentas, from Teaneck, New Jersey was born in 1944. She received a bachelor's degree from the Moore College of Art and a master's degree in Printmaking from NYU. Jane Walentas met David Walentas while searching for an apartment and the two soon married. Jane Walentas was an artist known for her restoration of Jane's Carousel in Brooklyn Bridge Park. She died July 5, 2020.
    In this interview, David Walentas (1938-) and Jane Zimmerman Walentas (1944-2020) describe their contrasting childhoods, their college years, their first meeting, and their later life together growing their real estate company. They also discuss raising their son, Jed, who now runs Two Trees. Jane Walentas describes her early career in fashion and cosmetic advertising in Italy and New York. David Walentas describes his work and travel in Europe, his previous marriage, and dealing with various groups in Brooklyn. Interview conducted by Julie Golia.
    Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Turin (Italy: Province); Wealth--United States; Corporate debt; Billionaires; Art patrons; Advertising departments; Real estate development; Jews, American; Walentas, David; Walentas, Jane Zimmerman; Moore College of Art; University of Virginia. School of Engineering and Applied Science. Division of Humanities